Finding Aid for G. Mennen Williams Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Governor's Papers
  - Chronological, 1949-1960
    - 1951
      - Military
        - Veterans
          - Education (Box 377)
          - Hospitalization (Box 377)
          - Organizations (Box 377)
          - Servicemen's Readjustment Allowance (Box 377)
          - Veterans Trust Fund (Box 377)
          - Vocational Rehabilitation (Box 377)
        - Selective Service
          - General (Box 377)
          - Re: Draft Boards (Box 377)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous (Box 393)
        - U. S. Senate (Box 393)
        - Agriculture, Department of (Box 393)
        - Air Force (Box 393)
        - Army (Box 393)
        - Attorney General (Box 393)
        - Budget (Box 393)
        - Commerce, Department of (Box 393)
        - Defense Mobilization (Box 393)
        - Economic Price Stabilizer (Box 393)
        - Federal Communications Commission (Box 393)
        - Federal Power Commission (Box 393)
        - Housing (Box 393)
        - Interior, Department of (Box 393)
        - Interstate Commerce Commission (Box 393)
        - Labor, Department of (Box 393)
        - Navy, Department of (Box 393)
        - Postmaster General (Box 393)
        - Reorganization of Government (Box 393)
        - Social Security Board (Box 393)
        - State, Department of (Box 393)
        - Treasury, Department of (Box 393)
        - Legislation (mainly constituent mail)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 393)
          - Aid to Education (Box 393)
          - Decennial Census (Box 393)
          - Iron Industry (Box 393)
          - Socialized Medicine (Box 393)
          - Tidelands
    - 1952
      - General Subjects
        - Administrative Reorganization of Government
          - General (Box 67)
          - Reports (Box 67)
        - Advertising (Box 67)
        - Aging Commission, 4 folders (Box 67)
        - Airlines; Aviation (Box 68)
        - American Legion (Box 68)
        - American Rededication Commission (Box 68)
        - Appointments (Box 68)
        - Bar (State) (Box 68)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 68)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 68)
        - CARE (Box 68)
        - Celebrations (Box 68)
        - Certificate - Outgoing (Box 68)
        - Charter Amendments (Box 68)
        - Cities (Box 68)
        - [box number eliminated during the 1983-84 reappraisal of the collection] (Box 69)
        - Communism (Box 70)
        - Community Chest (Box 70)
        - Complaints (Box 70)
        - Conferences
          - General (Box 70)
          - National Tax Association (Box 70)
        - Constitution (Box 70)
        - Consulates (Box 70)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 70)
        - Counties [arranged alphabetically] (Box 70)
        - Crime Commission (Box 70)
        - Defence Contracts Commission, 2 folders (Box 70)
        - Detroit, City of
          - General (Box 70)
          - Food and Drug Laboratory (Box 70)
        - Displaced Persons (Box 70)
        - Divorce (Box 70)
        - Drains (Box 71)
        - Editorials (Box 71)
        - Elections
          - General (Box 71)
          - Study Commission (Box 71)
        - Electoral College (Box 71)
        - Emergency Defense Contracts (see Defense Contracts Commission) (Box 71)
        - Employment (Box 71)
        - Executive Office (Box 71)
        - Fair Employment Practices Commission (Box 71)
        - Flood (Box 71)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 71)
        - Fulbright Scholarship (Box 71)
        - Full Employment Committee (see also Unemployment) (Box 71)
        - Gambling
          - General (Box 71)
          - Bingo (Box 71)
        - Girl Scouts (Box 71)
        - Governor's Conference
          - General (Box 71)
          - General Assembly (Box 71)
          - Houston, Texas (Box 71)
        - Governor's Mansion (Box 72)
        - Grand Jury (Box 72)
        - Hawaii (Box 72)
        - Head Tax (Box 72)
        - Health (Box 72)
        - Hi-Y (Box 72)
        - Honorary Membership (Box 72)
        - Housing, 2 folders (Box 72)
        - Housing Study Committee (Box 72)
        - Immigration (Box 72)
        - Income Tax (Box 72)
        - Infantile Paralysis (Box 72)
        - Interagency Council for Recreation (Box 72)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 72)
        - Investigation (Box 72)
        - Invitations - Outgoing
          - General (Box 72)
          - Empire Day Supper (Box 72)
          - Democratic Legislators' Dinner (Box 72)
        - Judgeship
          - General (Box 72)
          - Re John Libbers (Box 72)
        - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 72)
        - Labor (Box 72)
        - Land Grants (Box 72)
        - Legal Holidays (Box 72)
        - Legal Problems [A-Z] (Box 73)
        - Legion of Merit (James Lillis) (Box 73)
        - Legislative Reapportionment (Box 73)
        - Legislature, Members of (Box 73)
        - Message of Governor (Box 73)
        - Messages of Greeting, 3 folders (Box 73)
        - Migrant Labor (Box 73)
        - Music (Box 73)
        - Narcotics (Box 73)
        - Newspapers (Box 73)
        - Notary Public (Box 73)
        - Ordinances (Box 73)
        - Organizations (Box 74)
        - Physically Handicapped (Box 74)
        - Political
          - General, 3 folders (Box 74)
          - Racial Issues (Box 74)
          - Kiwanis Resolutions (Box 74)
        - Political Job (Box 74)
        - Postmaster (Box 74)
        - Public Utilities (Box 74)
        - Racial (Box 74)
        - Radio; TV
          - General (Box 74)
          - "Build Michigan" (Box 74)
          - Meet the Governor program, 2 folders (Box 74)
        - Recommendation (Box 74)
        - Red Cross (Box 75)
        - Red Stocking Club (Box 75)
        - Removal (Box 75)
        - Rent Control (Box 75)
        - Rent Control Advisory Board (Box 75)
        - Resolutions (Box 75)
        - Roads (Box 75)
        - Safety
          - General (Box 75)
          - President's Highway Safety Conference (Box 75)
        - St. Lawrence Seaway, 2 folders (Box 75)
        - Savings Bonds (Box 75)
        - Sex Deviates (Box 75)
        - Sponsor (Box 75)
        - Statements for Publication (Box 75)
        - States [arranged alphabetically] (Box 75)
        - Strikes (Box 75)
        - Taxation
          - General (Box 75)
          - Corporation Tax (Box 76)
        - Taxation Study Commission (Box 76)
        - Transportation (Box 76)
        - Transportation Study Commission (Box 76)
        - Unemployment
          - General (Box 76)
          - Meeting, Jan. 26 (Box 76)
          - Meetings, etc. (Box 76)
        - Unions (Box 76)
        - United World Federalists (Box 76)
        - Vacancy
          - General (Box 76)
          - Re Bert Dickerson (Box 76)
        - Wayne University (Box 76)
        - Wine Industry (Box 76)
        - World Government (Box 76)
        - Young Men's Christian Association (Box 76)
        - Youth Commission
          - General (Box 76)
          - Michigan Youth Advisory Council (Box 76)
        - Miscellaneous [A-J] (Box 76)
        - [Box number eliminated] (Box 77)
        - Miscellaneous [K-Z] (Box 78)
      - Boards and Commissions
        - Accident Fund (Box 78)
        - Accountancy, State Board of (Box 78)
        - Administrative Board
          - General (Box 78)
          - Meeting Files, Jan.-Apr. (Box 78)
          - Meeting Files, May-Dec. (Box 79)
          - Audit Reports; Progress Report of Various Departments, 1948-1952 (Box 79)
          - Accounting Division (Box 79)
          - Building and Construction Division (Box 79)
          - Motor Transport Division (Box 79)
          - Property Manager Division (Box 79)
          - Purchasing Division (Box 79)
          - Re State Personnel Council (Box 79)
        - Aeronautics, Department of
          - General (Box 80)
          - Re Detroit Airport (Box 80)
        - Agriculture, Department of
          - C. Figy, Director (Box 80)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 80)
          - Emergency Marketing Committee (Box 80)
          - Fair Grounds (Box 80)
          - Grapes (Box 80)
          - Strawberries (Box 80)
        - Agriculture, State Board of (Box 80)
        - Alcoholism Board (Box 80)
        - Apple Commission (Box 80)
        - Architects, Board of Registration (Box 80)
        - Athletic, Board of Control (Box 80)
        - Attorney General (Box 80)
        - Banking Commission (Box 80)
        - Barbers, Board of Examiners (Box 80)
        - Basic Science, Board of Examiners (Box 80)
        - Building Commission (Box 80)
        - Cherry Commission (Box 80)
        - Chiropody, Board of Registration (Box 80)
        - Chiropractic Examiners, Board of (Box 80)
        - Civil Service Commission
          - A. Rausch File (Box 80)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 80)
          - Joseph A. Craigen Case (Box 80)
        - Colleges, State
          - Miscellaneous (Box 80)
          - Central Michigan (Box 80)
          - Ferris (Box 80)
          - Michigan College of Mining and Technology (Box 80)
        - Colleges, State
          - Michigan State (Box 81)
          - Michigan State Normal College (Box 81)
          - Northern Michigan College of Education (Box 81)
          - University of Michigan
            - General (Box 81)
            - University Hospital (Box 81)
          - Western Michigan (Box 81)
        - Compilation Commission (Box 81)
        - Conservation Department
          - Gerald Eddy, Director (Box 81)
          - Reports; Printed Material (Box 81)
          - General (Box 81)
          - Geology and Soil Division (Box 81)
          - Interstate Oil Compact Commission (Box 81)
          - Lands Division (Box 81)
          - Parks and Recreation (Box 81)
        - Corporation and Securities Commission (Box 81)
        - Corrections Department
          - E. Brooks, Commissioner (Box 81)
          - Citizens Committee (Box 81)
          - General (Box 81)
          - Inmates [A-B] (Box 81)
          - Inmates [C-R] (Box 82)
          - Inmates [S-Z] (Box 83)
          - Pardons and commutation files [A-Z] (Box 83)
          - Prisons and reformatories
            - Ionia (Box 83)
            - Jackson Prison Riot
              - Special Reports (Box 83)
              - General [A-I] (Box 83)
              - General [J-Z] (Box 84)
            - Marquette (Box 84)
        - Cosmetology Board (Box 84)
        - Court of Claims Commission (Box 84)
        - Crippled Children Commission (Box 84)
        - Dentistry, Board of (Box 84)
        - Economic Development Department
          - General, 2 folders (Box 84)
          - Railway Express (Box 84)
          - Scrap Program (Box 84)
        - Education, State Board of
          - General (Box 84)
          - School for Blind (Box 84)
        - Employees Retirement Board, State (Box 84)
        - Employment Security Commission, Michigan
          - Max Horton, Director (Box 84)
          - General (Box 84)
          - Employment Service (Box 84)
          - Citizen Mail [A-Z] (Box 84)
          - Appeal Board (Box 84)
        - Escheats, State Board of (Box 84)
        - Fairs, Board of Manager of State (Box 84)
        - Fair, Upper Peninsula Board of Managers (Box 85)
        - Health Commission
          - A. Heustis, Commissioner (Box 85)
          - General (Box 85)
        - Highway, Department of
          - Charles M. Ziegler, Commissioner (Box 85)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 85)
          - Bridges and Ferries (Box 85)
        - Historical Commission (Box 85)
        - Hospital Survey and Construction (Box 85)
        - Huron-Clinton Metropolitan Authority (Box 85)
        - Insurance Commission
          - General (Box 85)
          - Lapeer Farmers [A-Z] (Box 85)
          - Prudential Strike (Box 85)
        - Interstate Cooperation Commission (Box 85)
        - Judicial Council of Michigan (Box 85)
        - Labor Department
          - General (Box 85)
          - Gogebic mine disaster inquest (Box 85)
        - Labor Mediation Board
          - George E. Bowles, Chairman (Box 86)
          - Balcer Bros. Motor Coach Company (Box 86)
          - Detroit Edison Co. (Box 86)
          - Pontiac City Lines (Box 86)
        - Law Examiners, Board of (Box 86)
        - Libraries, State Board of (Box 86)
        - Library, State (Box 86)
        - Lieutenant Governor (Box 86)
        - Liquor Control Commission
          - George Burke, Jr., Chairman (Box 86)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 86)
        - Mackinac Island Park Commission (Box 86)
        - Mackinac Straits Bridge Authority (Box 86)
        - Medicine, Board of Registration
          - General (Box 86)
          - Re Dr. James M. Schuele (Box 86)
        - Mental Health Department
          - Charles F. Wagg, Director (Box 86)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 86)
          - Reimbursement Report (Box 86)
          - Hospitals
            - Caro (Box 86)
            - Coldwater (Box 86)
            - Ionia (Box 87)
            - Kalamazoo (Box 87)
            - Lapeer (Box 87)
            - Mt. Pleasant (Box 87)
            - Newberry (Box 87)
            - Northville (Box 87)
            - Pontiac (Box 87)
            - Traverse City (Box 87)
            - Ypsilanti (Box 87)
        - Mortuary Science Board (Box 87)
        - Nurses and Trained Attendants, Board of Registration (Box 87)
        - Optometry, Board of Examiners (Box 87)
        - Osteopathic Registration and Examination, Board of (Box 87)
        - Pharmacy, Board of (Box 87)
        - Plumbing Board (Box 87)
        - Police, State
          - Joseph Childs, Commissioner (Box 87)
          - General (Box 87)
          - Rules and Regulations (liquefied petroleum gases) (Box 87)
          - Fire Inspection of Institutions (Box 87)
        - Port of Detroit (Box 87)
        - Port of Monroe (Box 87)
        - Private Employment Bureaus (Box 87)
        - Public Instruction
          - Lee Thurston, Superintendent (Box 87)
          - General (Box 87)
          - Report on sectarianism in Lake Linden schools (Box 87)
          - State Aid Program (Box 87)
        - Public School Employee Retirement Board (Box 87)
        - Public Service Commission
          - John McCarty, Chairman (Box 87)
          - General [A-Z] (Box 87)
        - Racing Commission (Box 87)
        - Revenue Department (Box 87)
        - Safety Commission (Box 88)
        - Secretary of State (Box 88)
        - Social Welfare Commission
          - W. J. Maxey, Director (Box 88)
          - General (Box 88)
          - Aid to Blind (Box 88)
          - Aid to Dependent Children (Box 88)
          - Boys' Vocational School (Box 88)
          - Children's Institute (Box 88)
          - Disabled Persons (Box 88)
          - Employment Institute for the Blind (Box 88)
          - Girls' Training School (Box 88)
          - Old Age Assistance
            - Claim on Property (Box 88)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 88)
          - Social Welfare letters [A-E] (Box 88)
          - Social Welfare letters [F-Z] (Box 89)
        - Soil Conservation Commission (Box 89)
        - Supreme Court (Box 89)
        - Tax Commission (Box 89)
        - Tax Appeals, Board of (Box 89)
        - Tourist Council (Box 89)
        - Treasurer, State (Box 89)
        - Tuberculosis Sanitorium Commission (Box 89)
        - Veterans Facility (Grand Rapids) (Box 89)
        - Vocational Education and Rehabilitation (Box 89)
        - Water Resources Commission
          - Milton Adams, Commissioner (Box 89)
          - General (Box 89)
          - Flood Control, 2 folders (Box 89)
          - Great Lakes Levels Conference (Box 89)
        - Waterways Commission
          - General (Box 90)
          - Harbors of Refuge (Box 90)
        - Workmen's Compensation Commission
          - General (Box 90)
          - Reports (Box 90)
      - Legislative Files
        - Regular Session (Box 332)
          - Governor's Messages (and related) (Box 332)
          - Bills Signed, 2 folders (Box 332)
          - Bills Vetoed, 2 folders (Box 332)
          - Memoranda, bills, etc. (Box 332)
          - Democratic Caucus Minutes (Box 332)
          - Constituent Mail
            - General [A-Z] (Box 332)
            - Administrative (state) agencies (Box 332)
            - Basic Science Act; Medical Practice Act (Box 333)
            - Civil Defense (Box 333)
            - Communism (Box 333)
            - Conservation (Box 333)
            - Court Administration (Box 333)
            - Dog Laws (Box 333)
            - Fraternal Order of Police (Box 333)
            - Judicial Circuit (Upper Peninsula) (Box 333)
            - Liquor Act (Box 333)
            - Marine Code (Box 333)
            - Military Board (Box 333)
            - Primary Election (Box 333)
            - Private Employment Bureau (Box 333)
            - Schools [A-J] (Box 333)
            - Schools [L-Z] (Box 334)
            - Unemployment; labor (Box 334)
              (miscellaneous)
            - Unemployment Compensation (Box 334)
            - White Pine Project (Box 334)
          - House Concurrent Resolution (State Building) (Box 334)
          - House (Recommendations on Bills) (Box 334)
          - Senate (Recommendations on Bills) (Box 334)
        - Special Session
          - December 18 (Box 334)
          - School Aid (Box 334)
          - Township Boards (Box 334)
      - Military
        - Adjutant General (Box 378)
        - Quartermaster General (Box 378)
        - Military Board (Box 378)
        - Civil Defense (Box 378)
        - Lester J. Maitland, State Director
          - General (Box 378)
          - Meeting File (Box 378)
          - Blood Typing (Box 378)
          - Compacts (Box 378)
          - Council (city and county) (Box 378)
          - County (Ingham) (Box 378)
          - Fire (Box 378)
          - Ground Observers (Box 378)
          - Labor (Box 378)
          - Medical (Box 378)
          - Mortuary (Box 378)
          - Religion (Box 378)
          - Veterans Technical Committee (Box 378)
        - National Guard
          - General (Box 378)
          - Air Unit (Box 378)
          - Armories (Box 378)
          - Mona Lake (Box 378)
          - Navy (Box 378)
        - State Troops (Box 378)
        - Veterans
          - General (Box 378)
          - Apprentice Training (Box 378)
          - Bonus (Box 378)
          - Hospitalization (Box 378)
          - On-Farm Training (Box 378)
          - Organizations (Box 378)
          - Veterans Readjustments Allowance (Box 378)
          - Veterans Trust Fund (Box 379)
            - Report (Box 379)
            - General [A-Z] (Box 379)
            - Flags (Box 379)
        - Selective Service (Box 379)
      - Federal
        - Miscellaneous (Box 394)
        - U. S. Senate (Box 394)
        - Agriculture, Department of (Box 394)
        - Air Force (Box 394)
        - Army (Box 394)
        - Attorney General (Box 394)
        - Commerce, Department of (Box 394)
        - Defense Mobilization (Box 394)
        - Economic Price Stabilizer (Box 394)
        - Federal Power Commission (Box 394)
        - Housing (Box 394)
        - Interior, Department of (Box 394)
        - International Joint Commission (Box 394)
        - Labor, Department of (Box 394)
        - Navy, Department of (Box 394)
        - Postmaster General (Box 394)
        - Social Security Board (Box 394)
        - State, Department of (Box 394)
        - Treasury, Department of (Box 394)
        - Legislation
          - Miscellaneous (Box 394)
          - Aid to Education (Box 394)
          - Mining Industry (Box 394)
          - Rent Control (Box 394)
          - Social Security (Box 394)
          - Socialized Medicine (Box 394)
          - Tidelands (Box 394)
    - 1953
      - General Subjects
        - Administrative Reorganization of Government
          - General (Box 394)
          - Reports (Box 90)
        - Adoption (Box 90)
        - Advertising (Box 90)
        - Aging Commission (Box 90)
        - Airlines; Aviation (Box 90)
        - Alaska (Box 90)
        - American-Korean Foundation (Box 90)
        - American Legion (Box 90)
        - Appointments (Box 90)
        - Bar (State) (Box 90)
        - Boy Scouts (Box 90)
        - Brag Book [samples] (Box 90)
        - Capital Punishment (Box 90)
        - Celebrations (Box 90)
        - Certificate - Outgoing (Box 90)
        - Charter Amendments [A-H] (Box 90)
        - [Box number eliminated during the 1983-84 reappraisal of the Williams collection] (Box 91)
        - Charter Amendments [I-Z] (Box 92)
        - Communism (Box 92)
        - Community Chest (Box 92)
        - Complaints (Box 92)
        - Conferences
          - General (Box 92)
          - National Tax Association (Box 92)
        - Constitution (Box 92)
        - Consulates (Box 92)
        - Council of State Governments (Box 92)
        - Counties [arranged alphabetically] (Box 92)
        - Countries
          - Canada (Box 93)
          - France (Box 93)
          - Israel (Box 93)
          - Netherlands (Box 93)
          - Yugoslavia (Box 93)
        - Crime Commission (Box 93)
        - Defence Contracts Commission (Box 93)
        - Detroit, City of
          - General (Box 93)
          - Food and Drug Laboratory (Box 93)
        - Disaster Relief
          - Flint, 3 folders (Box 93)
          - Port Huron (Box 93)
        - Displaced Persons (Box 93)
        - Divorce (Box 93)
        - Drains (Box 93)
        - Editorials (Box 93)
        - Elections
          - General (Box 93)
          - Study Commission (Box 93)
        - Employment (Box 93)
        - Executive Office (Box 93)
        - Fair Employment Practice Commission (Box 93)
        - Fire Prevention Committee (Box 93)
        - Friend of the Court (Box 93)
        - Fulbright Scholarship (Box 93)
        - Full Employment Committee (Box 93)
        - Gambling
          - General (Box 94)
          - Bingo [A-Z] (Box 94)
          - Numbers Racket Conference (Box 94)
        - Girl Scouts (Box 94)
        - Governor's Conference
          - General (Box 94)
          - Seattle, Wash. (Box 94)
          - Canadian trip (Box 94)
          - Washington, D.C., January (Box 94)
        - Governor's Mansion (Box 94)
        - Grand Jury (Box 94)
        - Hawaii (Box 94)
        - Hi-Y (Box 94)
        - Honorary Membership (Box 94)
        - Housing [A-Z] (Box 94)
        - Immigration (Box 94)
        - Income Tax (Box 94)
        - Infantile Paralysis (Box 94)
        - Interagency Council for Recreation (Box 94)
        - [Box number eliminated during the 1983-84 re-appraisal of the Williams collection] (Box 95)
        - Interviews [A-Z] (Box 96)
        - Invitations - Outgoing (Box 96)
        - Isle Royal Park Study Commission (Box 96)
        - Judgeship (Box 96)
        - Juvenile Delinquency (Box 96)
        - Labor (Box 96)
        - Legal Holidays (Box 96)
        - Legal Problems [A-Z] (Box 96)
        - Legislative Reapportionment (Box 96)
        - Legislature, Members of (Box 96)
        - Lobbyists (Box 96)
        - Message of Governor (Box 97)
        - Messages of Greeting (Box 97)
        - Migrant Labor (Box 97)
        - Music (Box 97)
        - Narcotics (Box 97)
        - Newspapers (Box 97)
        - Notary Public (Box 97)
        - Ordinances (Box 97)
        - Organizations (Box 97)
        - Philippine Islands (Box 97)
        - Physically Handicapped (Box 97)
        - Political [A-Z] (Box 97)
        - Political Job (Box 97)
        - Postmaster (Box 97)
        - Price Control (Box 97)
        - Public Utilities (Box 97)
        - Racial (Box 97)
        - Radio; TV
          - General, 2 folders (Box 97)
          - "Meet the Governor" program (Box 97)
        - Recommendations (Box 98)
        - Red Cross (Box 98)
        - Red Stocking Club (Box 98)
        - Removals (Box 98)
        - Rent Control (Box 98)
        - Resolutions (Box 98)